<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>St. George Mortgage Video Blog with Chantry Abbott</title>
    <description>Our mission at  is to be your best resource for St. George Mortgage advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about Mortgage. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Chantry Abbott.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 10:50:49 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 10:50:49 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Overpay Your Property Taxes</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/KukY3M6IS5Q?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you know if you’re being taxed accurately for the occupancy of your home? Here in Southern Utah, we have two property tax classifications: a primary home and a non-primary home. A primary home means either you or a full-time renter is living in the home as their primary residence. A non-primary home could be a vacation home or a part-time-use home that isn’t anyone’s primary residence. The tax rate for a non-primary home is about 45% higher than the tax rate for a primary home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge is that it’s sort of a guilty-until-proven-innocent situation. By that, I mean that in Washington County, they will assume your home is non-primary unless you go through the proper steps to register it as a primary home. Specifically for those of you who have bought a home this year and didn’t go through the correct process, you’ll be getting taxed at that non-primary rate. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The tax rate for a non-primary home is about 45% higher than the tax rate for a primary home.%20http://localhost:4000/dont-overpay-your-property-taxes.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The tax rate for a non-primary home is about 45% higher than the tax rate for a primary home.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three things you must do to make your home a primary home in the county’s eyes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. You have to have a Utah driver’s license with the same address as the house&lt;/strong&gt;. If you already have a Utah driver’s license, you can simply change the address online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. At closing, you have to fill out a form stating that the home is your primary residence and provide it to the Washington County assessor’s office.&lt;/strong&gt; Hopefully, your title company will have addressed this with you during your home-buying process. If you haven’t already, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://obweb.washco.utah.gov/AppNet/UnityForm.aspx?d1=ARYeXTIbRaS7sWPqFG9pI%2f5O%2b0Ksx5D9AOrgNCT327kaJNsCeeAt5rHo0zSt4HRvt%2bL%2fuZPl2qJKY7eh0lQQV9WngVceie5kb1XDRL8MjjaTEUXiaCAEtDoFM4dN%2fcmcOHxtwYOBwdcru41C1IzshJk1WCKevY%2bnQ8JOHury6mRHEgYXnjAud8UZqrdvaIw%2ffZpApygb8%2bAY8BziCqKJhxict3Z294yoO4v4C3nv1k54&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to fill out the form online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Make sure that the listed market value is correct.&lt;/strong&gt; If the market value shown on your bill is higher than you think, you can dispute the value with the county. Since you’ll need evidence, you may need to get an appraisal so that the county can see what your home’s actual value is; they can’t legally charge you more than the true value of your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hate to see our friends and family pay too much in property taxes, so if you have any questions or need some assistance, feel free to give us a call or send an email. We’d love to be a resource for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please consult a tax advisor for more information. NMLS ID #309670, I am authorized to do business in the state of Utah. Guild Mortgage Company; Equal Housing Opportunity; NMLS #3274. nmlsconsumeraccess.org. All loans subject to underwriter approval. Terms and conditions apply, subject to change without notice. For more licensing information, please visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.guildmortgage.com/licensing/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Licensing.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 10:51:30 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/dont-overpay-your-property-taxes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/dont-overpay-your-property-taxes.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Zero-Down Programs You May Qualify For</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/cvD6bH_wuLM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most homebuyers think you have to have a lot of money in the bank or come in with a big down payment to buy a home. That’s just not true. Today I want to share four loan programs you may qualify for that don’t require a down payment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. A VA Loan.&lt;/strong&gt; This loan is only for people who have served in the military or been in the national guard for six years. You will typically need a credit score of 620 to qualify, but these loans offer great benefits and interest rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Rural housing.&lt;/strong&gt; This zero-down program comes from the United States Department of Agriculture, and it applies to homes in rural areas. The areas around St. George that would qualify for this program are Ivins and outwards, Hurricane and outwards, and all of Cedar City. You will need around a 600 credit score, and there are some income limits. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The Guild grant gives you a second mortgage that can be forgiven if you make your payments on time.%20http://localhost:4000/4-zero-down-programs-you-may-qualify-for.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The Guild grant gives you a second mortgage that can be forgiven if you make your payments on time.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Utah housing.&lt;/strong&gt; This program is specific to Utah, and it works with a normal FHA loan. On that first mortgage, you’ll have a down payment of 3.5%, but this program will give you a second mortgage to cover that down payment. You need a credit score of 660 or better, but it’s a great option in this area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Guild grant.&lt;/strong&gt; We offer this grant program here at Guild Mortgage. It gives you a second mortgage of 3.5% that can be forgiven if you make the first mortgage’s payments on time for the first 36 months. You only need a credit score of 620, but it’s an amazing grant that we love to offer to our clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Gifted money&lt;/strong&gt;. This bonus option is to simply ask for cash gifts to use as a down payment. Let’s say that you’re having a wedding. Instead of asking for gifts, you could ask for cash instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would love to help you with any questions you have. If you’re concerned about qualifying or your credit score is a little low, we can make a plan to solve that. Even if you’re not planning on buying for a while, we’d love to connect with you now and build you a roadmap. Feel free to call, email, or schedule a time to meet us here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;NMLS ID #309670, I am authorized to do business in the state of Utah. Guild Mortgage Company; Equal Housing Opportunity; NMLS #3274. nmlsconsumeraccess.org. All loans subject to underwriter approval. Terms and conditions apply, subject to change without notice. For more licensing information, please visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.guildmortgage.com/licensing/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Licensing.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 16:40:29 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/4-zero-down-programs-you-may-qualify-for.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/4-zero-down-programs-you-may-qualify-for.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Our Credit Approval Protection Program Works</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7dAUEuvgl14?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re constantly being asked, “How can a buyer win an offer in this competitive real estate market?” It’s especially hard when you’re competing with cash offers. Today we’re going to share how we accomplish this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like the mortgage industry is broken. You get pre-approved with a loan officer, then you go under contract, then that lending company works with the underwriting team to finally get your loan approved. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve all heard horror stories of delays, declined files, and changed programs. &lt;strong&gt;This usually happens as a result of the company not uncovering everything in your file at the beginning of the process.&lt;/strong&gt; A flimsy pre-qualification or pre-approval is not good. It takes 30 days for them to find out there’s a problem after you’re under contract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=With this program, the legwork on your loan is done ahead of time.%20http://localhost:4000/our-credit-approval-protection-program.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“With this program, the legwork on your loan is done ahead of time.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing we like to do differently is our &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.guildmortgage.com/homebuyer-protection/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Credit Approval Protection Program&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;With this program, we fully underwrite your file before you even start your home search.&lt;/strong&gt; The mortgage will still take 30 days to fund, but we carve out the first two weeks to put in the extra effort to know that your approval is 100% good. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Credit Approval Protection Program helps you make a strong offer to the seller with a quick closing deadline. You can remove financing contingencies and have the peace of mind that the leg work on your loan is basically done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a really neat solution, and our buyers are winning against cash offers with it. If you have any questions about the program or anything else related to mortgages, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;br /&gt;—&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;NMLS ID #309670, I am authorized to do business in the state of Utah. Guild Mortgage Company; Equal Housing Opportunity; NMLS #3274. nmlsconsumeraccess.org. All loans subject to underwriter approval. Terms and conditions apply, subject to change without notice. For more licensing information, please visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.guildmortgage.com/licensing/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Licensing.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 18:00:41 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/our-credit-approval-protection-program.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/our-credit-approval-protection-program.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome To My Blog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know how to guide you through a changing marketplace to help you secure the best loans and the best rates. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our market remains busy, and I know how to keep you updated on everything that’s going on with interest rates, mortgage programs, and the real estate world as a whole.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I’ll be posting two monthly video messages on this blog to keep you updated. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They will be valuable and useful in helping you stay on top of what’s happening in the lending community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check back because content will be coming soon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m excited to keep you updated!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 03:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-my-blog.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-my-blog.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
