<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>St. George Mortgage Podcast with Chantry Abbott</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Chantry Abbott.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Chantry Abbott</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2021-11-01 14:01:23 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Chantry Abbott</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top Mortgage agents, local Mortgage agents, find a Mortgage agent, houses for sale in St. George, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, Mortgage, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>chantrya@guildmortgage.net</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Chantry Abbott</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Chantry Abbott</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top Mortgage agents, local Mortgage agents, find a Mortgage agent, houses for sale in St. George, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, Mortgage, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for home loans in the St. George Area</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Chantry Abbott.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Our Credit Approval Protection Program Works</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/our-credit-approval-protection-program.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Chantry Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2021-10-21 18:00:41 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Chantry+Abbott/Videos/How+Our+Credit+Approval+Protection+Program+Works.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We’re constantly being asked, “How can a buyer win an offer in this competitive real estate market?” It’s especially hard when you’re competing with cash offers. Today we’re going to share how we accomplish this.

I feel like the mortgage industry is broken. You get pre-approved with a loan officer, then you go under contract, then that lending company works with the underwriting team to finally get your loan approved. 

We’ve all heard horror stories of delays, declined files, and changed programs. This usually happens as a result of the company not uncovering everything in your file at the beginning of the process. A flimsy pre-qualification or pre-approval is not good. It takes 30 days for them to find out there’s a problem after you’re under contract.

“With this program, the legwork on your loan is done ahead of time.”

One thing we like to do differently is our Credit Approval Protection Program. With this program, we fully underwrite your file before you even start your home search. The mortgage will still take 30 days to fund, but we carve out the first two weeks to put in the extra effort to know that your approval is 100% good. 

Our Credit Approval Protection Program helps you make a strong offer to the seller with a quick closing deadline. You can remove financing contingencies and have the peace of mind that the leg work on your loan is basically done.

It’s a really neat solution, and our buyers are winning against cash offers with it. If you have any questions about the program or anything else related to mortgages, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.—NMLS ID #309670, I am authorized to do business in the state of Utah. Guild Mortgage Company; Equal Housing Opportunity; NMLS #3274. nmlsconsumeraccess.org. All loans subject to underwriter approval. Terms and conditions apply, subject to change without notice. For more licensing information, please visit Licensing.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Chantry+Abbott/Videos/How+Our+Credit+Approval+Protection+Program+Works.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Chantry+Abbott/Videos/How+Our+Credit+Approval+Protection+Program+Works.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here’s how our Credit Approval Protection Program can help you win.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Chantry Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here’s how our Credit Approval Protection Program can help you win.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top Mortgage agents, local Mortgage agents, find a Mortgage agent, houses for sale in St. George, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, Mortgage, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Welcome To My Blog</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-my-blog.html</link>
        
        <author>Chantry Abbott</author>
        <pubDate>2021-10-01 03:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Welcome!

I know how to guide you through a changing marketplace to help you secure the best loans and the best rates. 

Our market remains busy, and I know how to keep you updated on everything that’s going on with interest rates, mortgage programs, and the real estate world as a whole.

So, I’ll be posting two monthly video messages on this blog to keep you updated. 

They will be valuable and useful in helping you stay on top of what’s happening in the lending community.

Check back because content will be coming soon!

I’m excited to keep you updated!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>My monthly messages will provide you with interest rates, mortgage programs, and the real estate world as a whole.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Chantry Abbott</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>My monthly messages will provide you with interest rates, mortgage programs, and the real estate world as a whole.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top Mortgage agents, local Mortgage agents, find a Mortgage agent, houses for sale in St. George, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, Mortgage, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Chantry Abbott</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Chantry Abbott</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Chantry Abbott.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
